KISHORE KUMAR

Cloud & DevOps Engineer

Chennai, India | +91 733-894-6227 | kishoreshalini4@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Working as a Cloud & DevOps Engineer with having hands on experience on various devops and CICD tools like **Jenkins**, **terraform**, **Ansible**, **Docker**, **Kubernetes**, using **Gitops** principles for more efficient application delivery and Cloud service provider **AWS**.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Develop, test, deploy, maintain and improve software to meet requirements.
- Design and develop test automation code.
- Perform basic analysis and design for clearly defined requirements.
- Contribute to estimates required for user stories based on business requirements, specifications and designs.
- Comply with and contribute to SDLC standards and CD/CI procedures to ensure consistency.
- Monitor progress against task estimates to provide status.
- Provide technical support and troubleshooting for applications across environments.
- Maintain existing code base, monitoring for failures in non-prod environments.
- Support changes during quality assurance, user acceptance testing, and post implementation to ensure integrity of application.
- Share technical expertise; guide and mentor others to maximize team effectiveness and quality.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CloudifyOps Pvt Ltd | Bengaluru, India

Associate DevOps Engineer | March 2022 - Present

- Evaluation/design/development/deployment of additional technologies and automation for managed services on AWS
- Maintain GIT repositories, handling releases and branching activities for GIT HUB.
- Worked on implementing automation using AWS Lambda service with Python.
- Worked closely with developers in implementing **CICD** and migration of the infrastructure.
- Hands on experience in designing the infrastructure using Terraform and Ansible.
- Hands on experience with designing and implementing CICD jobs with Jenkins.
- Worked on containerizing the existing application on Docker and Orchestrated using Kubernetes.
- Hands on experience in architecture practices like Well-Architected Framework.
- Hands on experience in implementing GitOps principles using **Argo CD** with **Kubernetes Deployments**.
- Worked closely with Clients in implementing the Disaster Recovery Activity (DR) for maintaining application's maximum availability.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HTC Global Services | Chennai, India

Process Associate (DevOps) | November 2020 - March 2022

- Experience on AWS cloud services like **EC2**, **S3**, **ELB**, **VPC**, **Auto scaling groups**.
- Setting up Cloud watch and IAM for installing, configuring and troubleshooting on various amazon images
- Having knowledge in hosting web application in EC2 instances like Windows and Linux
- Maintain GIT repositories, handling releases and branching activities for GIT HUB.
- Configured Jenkins jobs for testing and complete CI/CD.
- Good knowledge in using basic **Linux** commands in Linux instances.
- Worked with container-based deployments using Docker, Docker images and Docker Hub.

Sutherland Global Services | Chennai, India

Technical Support | May 2020 - October 2022

- Take ownership of customer issues reported and see problems through to resolution.
- Research, diagnose, troubleshoot and identify solutions to resolve customer issues
- Provide prompt and accurate feedback to customers
- Follow the SLA for issues with respect to the severity.
- Documents technical issues and develops test cases to address similar concerns in the future.
- Diagnose and troubleshoots network issues to avoid downtime.
- Monitor cases and handles critical customer accounts.
- Worked with various teams to resolve problems.

Amalorpvam Hr. Sec. School | Puducherry, India

Desktop Support Engineer | May 2017 - September 2019

- Responding to client inquiries.
- Provided technical support to users.
- Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
- Provided instructions or directly sets up desktop hardware.
- Assisted with installation of computer software and operating system updates.
- Recorded logs of rendered support.
- Installing and maintaining hardware and computer peripherals.
- Installing and upgrading operating systems and computer software.
- Troubleshooting networking and connection issues.
- Advising on software or hardware upgrades.
- Providing basic training in computer operation and management.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2020 | Alagappa University, India

Bachelor of Computer Science - Software Engineering

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (Click to view)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- AWS Services: EC2, IAM, S3, ECR, EKS, RDS, Lambda, ElastiCache, EventBridge, SNS, SQS, WAF, SSM, Well-Architected Framework
- CICD Tools: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Argo CD
- Infrastructure as a Code: TerraformConfiguration Management: Ansible
- Containerization: Docker
- Container Orchestration: Kubernetes, GitOps
- Scripting Language: Python

PORTFOLIO

about.me | LinkedIn (Click to view)